(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-05T01:52:58.915844",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください／声出し応援OKです
Attention to all attendees:
Please be aware of flashing lights / Cheering loudly is OK
二次販売グッズ：応援セット
Second-round Merchandise: Support Set
個別グッズ：おにぎりゃーらいと／おにぎりTシャツ
おにぎりペンライトポーチ／マフラータオル
Individual Goods: Onigiriya Light / Onigiri T-Shirt
Penlight Pouch / Muffler Towel
個別グッズ：エコバッグ／缶バッジ
シュシュキーホルダー／クッション／アクリルスタンド
Individual Goods: Eco Bag / Can Badge
Scrunchie Key Ring / Cushion / Acrylic Stand
猫又おかゆ 2nd Live「ぽるそにゃりぃのすぺーす」
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live: Personyality's Space
ファンの皆様からの応援メッセージ
Support messages from fans
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください／声出し応援OKです
Attention to all attendees:
Please be aware of flashing lights / Cheering loudly is OK
二次販売グッズ：応援セット
Second-round Merchandise: Support Set
個別グッズ：おにぎりゃーらいと／おにぎりTシャツ
おにぎりペンライトポーチ／マフラータオル
Individual Goods: Onigiriya Light / Onigiri T-Shirt
Penlight Pouch / Muffler Towel
個別グッズ：エコバッグ／缶バッジ
シュシュキーホルダー／クッション／アクリルスタンド
Individual Goods: Eco Bag / Can Badge
Scrunchie Key Ring / Cushion / Acrylic Stand
二次販売グッズ
[Second-round Merchandise Sale]
猫又おかゆ 2nd Live「べるそにゃ～りすぺくと」お祝いメッセージ
[Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live \"Personya Respect\" Congratulatory Messages]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
[The concert will begin shortly. Please wait a moment.]
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
[Attention: To All Visitors]
応援セット
[Support Set]
お祝いメッセージ
[Congratulatory Messages]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will begin shortly. Please wait a moment.
演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください。声出し応援OKです。
Please be aware of flashing lights. Vocal cheering is allowed.
二次販売グッズ
Second Round Merchandise Lineup
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will begin shortly. Please wait a moment.
協賛
Sponsors
...そうだな
...seems like it...
あ、こっちこっちこっち！
Ah, over here, over here!
今日二人じゃないんすね
We're not alone today?
え？二人？
Huh? Just the two of us?
さっきの...
The people...
ここで会った人たち
...we just met here.
え？
What?
心で！
In my heart!
Joyにいこうぜ！
Let's Joy!
JOYSOUND X1
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live ぺるそにゃ・りすぺくと
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live: Pero Soniya Respect
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will begin shortly. Please wait a moment.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください
Attention to all attendees:
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK!
二次販売グッズ
応援セット
Second Sales Merchandise
Support Set
おにぎりゃーらいと　おにぎりTシャツ
おにぎりペンライトポーチ　マフラータオル
Onigiryas Light / Onigiri T-Shirt
Onigiri Penlight Pouch / Muffler Towel
ぺるそにゃ〜エコバッグ　シュシュキーホルダー
クッション　缶バッジ　アクリルスタンド
Pero Soniya Eco Bag / Scrunchie Key Ring
Cushion / Can Badge / Acrylic Stand
本日は
Thank you for coming today to
猫又おかゆ セカンドライブ
Nekomata Okayu's 2nd Live,
『ぱるそにぁりすぺくと』にご来場いただき
"Parusonia Respect"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
めっちゃ盛り上がってくれてるじゃん。
Wow, you guys are already so hyped!
え、みんな、1たす1は？
Hey, everyone, what's one plus one?
にー！
Two!
あははは！
Ahahaha!
いいね、今日ラグないね。
Nice! There's no lag today.
はい、もぐもぐおかゆです。こんばんはー。
Alright, this is Mogumogu Okayu. Good evening!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To make sure you enjoy the concert to the end, I have a few announcements.
いい返事。
Nice response!
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Taking photos, recording audio, or filming during the performance is strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず、近くのスタッフへおしらせください。
If you feel unwell, please don't push yourself and notify a nearby staff member.
会場内での押し合い、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、
Pushing, diving, or throwing things onto the stage
他のみんなに迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は、一切禁止です。
and any other behaviors that disrupt the show or bother others are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って、盛り上がってくださいね。
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
イェーイ！
Yay!
また、本公演は映像配信及び写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合があります。
Also, please note that filming and photography cameras are in the venue and may capture the audience.
これらの映像や写真は、プロモーションなどに使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
These recordings and photos may be used for promotional purposes, so please keep that in mind.
ここまでの影ナレ、実は振り仮名をね、付けてもらったので、
To be honest, they put furigana on the script for this pre-show announcement,
うふふふ、スラスラ読めてるでしょ？
hehe, so that's why I could read it so smoothly!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「おかゆセカンド」です。
Also, the official hashtag for the live is "Okayu Second".
ハッシュタグを使って、たくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいな。
I'd love it if you'd post a lot using the hashtag to hype things up!
お願いします。それでは、開演までもう少しです。
Please do! Well, there's only a little time left before the show starts.
待ちに待った声出しありのセカンドライブ、
Our long-awaited 2nd Live where cheering is allowed!
おにぎりゃーの声を、いっぱい聞かせてね！
Let me hear your voices loud and clear, Onigiri-ya!
おかゆ！ おかゆ！ おかゆ！
Okayu! Okayu! Okayu!
全然いらないじゃんか
I don't need any of this, do I?
分かってくれないじゃんか
You're not going to understand me, are you?
まあ仕方ないなって思えはしないけど
Though I can't just think, "Well, it can't be helped."
全然笑えないじゃんか
I can't laugh at all, can I?
面白くなくなりじゃんか
It's not getting any fun, is it?
あぁこんなもんかって余計な期待か
Ah, is that all it is? Just useless anticipation?
そもそも話し君の事とかも求めてる事とか分からないや
In the first place, I don't get you or what you're even looking for.
どろどろになるまでにこんな感情 火傷しちゃうくらい あちあち
These feelings are boiling hot, enough to burn me before they melt away.
笑顔に甘えてるんじゃないの？
Aren't you just taking advantage of my smile?
優しさに溶かされてるんじゃないの？
Aren't you just being melted by my kindness?
応えが欲しいわけじゃなくって
It's not that I want you to give me an answer,
たまに思うだけ気にしないで
I just think about it sometimes, so don't mind me.
ようこそ、にゃりーな！
Welcome to Nyarena!
あっかんべーをしましょう 世界はいらないのよ
Let's stick out our tongues, we don't need this world.
いいよ いいよ 押し殺しちゃっていいわ
It's fine, it's fine, you can just smother those feelings.
あっかんべーを忘れたら 目一杯のドキドキしよう
If you forget to stick out your tongue, let's make your heart race as much as possible.
いいよ いいよ もっと虜になれたら開けましょう
It's fine, it's fine, once you're even more captivated, let's open it up.
知りもしないくせに分かったフリ それで好きだなんて面白いや
Pretending to understand when you don't know a thing, and saying you love me—how amusing.
諦めの鼓動 裏で鳴るハロー 混ざり合うハートは
The heartbeat of resignation, a "hello" ringing in the background, our mixing hearts are...
きょ、きょ、きょ、きょ！
Kyo, kyo, kyo, kyo!
どこまでを許せばいいのかって
How far should I forgive you?
ぐるぐる回る妄想分かって
Please understand this spinning delusion.
頭の中をタトゥーがループ
A tattoo loops inside my head.
僕か猛毒はどっち、どっち？
Is it me or the deadly poison? Which one?
ちぎれた僕食って大満足？ 腹満たせりゃそれで辛くないか
Eating my torn pieces and totally satisfied? If your stomach is full, isn't that painful?
ここにメインディッシュありますよ
Here is your main dish.
お口拭いてお代わりはどうだい
Wipe your mouth, how about a second helping?
ちぎれた僕食って大満足？ 腹満たせりゃそれで辛くないか
Eating my torn pieces and totally satisfied? If your stomach is full, isn't that painful?
ここにメインディッシュありますよ
Here is your main dish.
お口拭いてお代わりはどうだい
Wipe your mouth, how about a second helping?
あっかんべーのつづきとか思ったってやらないのよ
Even if you expected a continuation of the "Akkanbee," I won't do it.
だって だって 虚しくなるだけだから
Because, because, it will only make things empty.
あっかんべーを忘れたら 目一杯笑顔になれるよ
If you forget the "Akkanbee," you can smile with all your might.
だって だって そうだ僕は
Because, because, that's right, I am...
あっかんべーをしましょう 世界はいらないのよ
Let's stick out our tongues, we don't need this world.
いいよ いいよ 押し殺しちゃっていいわ
It's fine, it's fine, you can just smother those feelings.
あっかんべーを忘れたら 目一杯のドキドキしよう
If you forget to stick out your tongue, let's make your heart race as much as possible.
いいよ いいよ もっと虜になれたら開けましょう
It's fine, it's fine, once you're even more captivated, let's open it up.
ね、ね、びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, did it surprise you?
もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Could it be you've gotten scared?
そう、全部なっちゃって
Yes, let it all become like that,
驚かせてごめんね
Sorry for startling you.
ね、ね、びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, did it surprise you?
もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Could it be you've gotten scared?
そう、全部なっちゃって
Yes, let it all become like that,
どちらが僕でしょうか？
Which one of us is me?
僕の
Deep within...
深くで
...me,
君は
...you...
言葉を
...were waiting...
待っていたんだ
...for words.
倒れない
So you wouldn't...
ように
...fall down,
伸ばした
you reached out...
願いに
...and to that wish,
応えていくだけだよ
I'm only going to respond.
与えることしかできないよ
I can only give to you...
隙間から見えた輪郭保存
...the outline visible through the gap.
ほら 模様のように
Look, like a pattern,
ぼくの色じゃなくても
even if it's not my color,
素敵に着こなせるよ
you can wear it beautifully.
きみの視界のぼくは
How does the "me" in your field of vision
何の色に見えますか
look to you? What color does it seem?
はりめぐらしたセンサで
With the sensors spread all around,
理由もなく好きになる
I'll fall in love for no reason.
なみだ お届けするから
Because I'll deliver tears to you,
衣装を纏い 待っていてくれ
put on your costume and wait for me.
風を引くまで 濡れた顔に
Until we catch a cold, on your wet face,
触れることができたらいいのにな
if only I could touch it...
あたしの色は 誰かの言葉
My color is someone else's words,
受け取るために 花を咲かせるの
blooming flowers to receive them.
なみだ枯れたら 無限級数
If my tears dry up, it's an infinite series.
ぼくは 目をひらいて 口をあけ
I open my eyes, open my mouth,
息をしないで 色をのむ
without breathing, I swallow the colors.
きみは ぼくから 何が見える
What can you see from me?
って想像する心が 欲しかった
I wanted a heart that imagines that.
声をからすことのないように
So that my voice won't run hoarse,
ぼくにずっと 色を注ぎ足してね
keep pouring colors into me forever.
きみの視界のぼくは
The "me" in your field of vision,
きみの世界のぼくを
the "me" in your world,
どんな色に塗りますか
what color will you paint me?
季節にさらわれるまでは
Until we are swept away by the seasons,
理由もなく手を
let's hold hands...
なみだを知りたいから
Because I want to know tears,
衣装を纏う五感をくれ
clothe me in costumes, give me senses.
そばにいるほど 移るぼくで
The closer I am, the more I change,
飾ることができたらいいのに
if only I could decorate myself.
湿っぽい 季節の デコレーション
A damp season's decoration,
咲かせるための 依存関係
a dependent relationship to make it bloom.
残しておいた 余白できみの感覚を奪う
Depriving your senses in the margins I left behind.
生ものの骨はえぐいから
Since bones in raw food are harsh,
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
make sure to cook them thoroughly before eating.
サービスはずるいから
Since complimentary service is unfair,
それも以心伝心のレシピ
that too is a recipe for telepathy.
みんな自分 偽ってるかい？
Is everyone faking who they are?
嘘の万国博覧会
An international exposition of lies.
みんな自分 偽ってるかい？
Is everyone faking who they are?
痛みに飼い慣らして保存版
Taming the pain...
さあ
Come on!
嫌いだけど好き
I hate you, but I love you.
不味くても美味しい
It tastes bad, but it's delicious.
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll put on a mascot suit and give you a hug.
泣かせないように
So I won't make you cry,
怒らせないように
so I won't make you mad,
ちょうどよく君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you in perfect harmony.
猫かぶり 猫かぶりな
Play innocent, play innocent!
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you when you're a little cowardly.
猫かぶり 猫かぶりな
Play innocent, play innocent!
取り繕ってる僕が好き
I like myself when I'm keeping up appearances.
様子を知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you when you know how things are.
思惑と意図では大違い
Expectations and intentions are vastly different.
建前も用法用量次第
Our public face also depends on the dosage.
みんな自分 疑ってるかい？
Is everyone doubting themselves?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely marching band.
みんな自分 疑ってるかい？
Is everyone doubting themselves?
首輪の鈴鳴らして
Ring the bell on your collar...
うにゃあ！
Meow!
災難だけどハッピー
It's a disaster, but I'm happy.
しんどくても平気
Even if it's tough, I'm okay.
甘皮剥けない夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a dream where you won't get hangnails.
傷つけないように
So I won't hurt you,
追い詰めないように
so I won't corner you,
夜明けまで君とふざけ合うのだ
I want to goof around with you until dawn.
猫かぶり 猫かぶりな
Play innocent, play innocent!
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you when your claws are tucked in.
猫かぶり 猫かぶりな
Play innocent, play innocent!
涙を見せない僕が好き
I like myself when I don't show my tears.
痛みを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love you when you know pain.
もぐもぐおかゆー！
Mogu mogu Okayu!
みんな、今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming today!
ここからのね 「君はねこねこ」「わすれな」のねこの部分は
For the next part, during the "cat" parts of "Kimi wa Neko Neko" and "Wasurena",
みんなにも一緒に歌ってほしいなと思って
I want everyone to sing along with me!
いい？
Alright?
「君はねこねこ」って大きい声で歌うんだよ
Sing "You are a cat, cat" out loud!
行くよー！
Here we go!
せーの！
One, two...
猫 猫
...cat, cat,
お砂付きの猫
the cat with sand on it.
君は人 人
You are a human, human,
お砂付きの人
a human with sand on them.
あれはUFO UFO
That is a UFO, UFO,
お砂付きのUFO
a UFO with sand on it.
君は猫 猫
You are a cat, cat,
お砂付きの猫
the cat with sand on it.
君は人 人
You are a human, human,
お砂付きの人
a human with sand on them.
あれはUFO UFO
That is a UFO, UFO,
お砂付きのUFO
a UFO with sand on it.
君は誰 誰
Who are you, who?
特別な人
A special someone.
猫かぶりの
Wearing a cat persona...
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, even if you're a bit cowardly.
君も僕も交わらない世界で
In a world where you and I don't intersect,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
since it's a place where we finally belong.
猫かぶりの
Wearing a cat persona...
ちょいと尖ってる僕が好き
I like myself when I'm a bit edgy.
君も僕も惑わしている世界で
In a world where both you and I are confused,
明日もまた会えたらいいの
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
猫かぶりの
Wearing a cat persona...
良さを知っている君が好きだよ
I like you because you know my good parts.
3回目の、もぐもぐ！
For the third time, Mogu Mogu!
イェーイ！
Yay!
もうさ、陰アナも含めて3回も『もぐもぐおかゆ』って言っちゃったよ
I've already said "Mogu Mogu Okayu" three times, including the pre-show announcement!
うーー！
Ooooh!
このね、ライブの空気感で、みんな僕が変なこと言っても『イェーイ！』って言ってくれるからね
With this live concert atmosphere, everyone still goes "Yay!" even if I say something weird.
これですよ。ということでね、やっとこの日が来ました。横浜！
This is it. So, this day has finally come. Yokohama!
お邪魔しております
Thank you for having me.
いや、もうさ、あっという間すぎたんだよ、この時間まで
I mean, the time leading up to this point went by in a flash.
さっきまで僕ね、お弁当食べてたんだけど
I was eating a bento box just a little while ago.
え、食べるでしょ？お弁当
What? Of course you eat bento!
僕の食べたお弁当は、何お弁当でしょうか？
What kind of bento do you think I ate?
何て言ってるかよく分かんないけど
I can't really tell what you guys are saying,
え、ちなみにさ、
but by the way,
おにぎり温めたよって人、手挙げて
raise your hand if you heated up your onigiri!
あ、最高、最高。見えてるよ、ありがとうね
Ah, awesome, awesome. I can see you, thank you!
ヤッホー
Yoo-hoo!
自然とR席の、配信チケットを見てるみんなも、見えてるからね！
Of course, I can see everyone in the R-seats and those watching on stream too!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということでですね、皆さんなんと、お気づきだと思いますが、本日のバンドは生演奏となっております！
So, as you all have probably noticed, today's band is performing live!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やっぱね、生演奏、お腹に来るよね、お腹に
Live music really hits you right in the gut, doesn't it?
うわ、来る、お腹に来るぞ！
Wow, it really does! It hits you right in the gut!
イェーイ！僕のさっき食べたお弁当も多分、腹で、
Yay! The bento I ate earlier is probably in my stomach,
はっはっ、ってなってるわ、きっと。あはははっ
going "thump, thump" right now, surely. Hahaha!
えー、あとですね、残念なお知らせがございます
And next, I have some sad news.
あ、これ定番だよね。もう一回やりたい、もう一回やりたい。いくよ？
Ah, this is a classic routine. I want to do it again, I want to do it again. Ready?
ここで、残念なお知らせがあります
At this point, I have some sad news.
なんと、冒頭無料チラ見せはここで終了です
Believe it or not, the free preview at the start ends here!
ごめんね。概要欄とか、あとYouTubeのチラ見せにはさ、固定してるコメントのところからチケット買えるので、ぜひお願いします
Sorry. You can buy tickets from the description or the pinned comment on the YouTube preview, so please do!
はい、後悔はね、させません。約束いたしますので。はい
Yes, I won't let you regret it. I promise. Yes.
うーー！
Ooooh!
配信で楽しんでる人は、ハッシュタグ『#おかゆセカンド』でいっぱい呟いてくれると嬉しいです！
If you're enjoying the stream, I'd love it if you tweeted a lot using the hashtag #OkayuSecond!
ありがとう
Thank you!
あとね、みんなさ、ポチポチポチポチ、ペンライト変えてくれてたじゃん
Also, you guys were clicking away changing your penlight colors, right?
実は、この僕のマイク、あ、離すと聞こえなくなるわ。あはははっ
Actually, this microphone of mine... Ah, if I move it away, you can't hear me. Hahaha!
こ、このマイクの、色が実はね、
Th-The color of this microphone is actually...
ペンライトの色になってるから！
changing to match the penlight color!
何色にするか分かんない人は、このペンライト...
So if you don't know what color to pick, this penlight...
...色を参考にしてみてください。
...please use the colors as a reference.
遠くで見えづらい人は、
For those of you far away who can't see well,
あんまりね、大きな声じゃ言えないですけど、
I shouldn't really say this out loud, but...
とりあえず紫にしとけば間違いないから。
...if you just set it to purple, you can't go wrong.
間違いありません本当に！
You really can't go wrong, seriously!
ということで、
And so,
今日は色んな表情の僕を楽しんでいってください！
please enjoy all my different expressions today!
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Now then, let's go to the next song!
キスだけで
With just a kiss...
いいからね
...it will be fine, okay?
そばにいて
Stay by my side...
私を
...and me...
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.